{
	"cards": [
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-1",
			"front": "A young person age 12 to 18 years.",
			"back": "adolescent"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-2",
			"front": "An event that causes unresponsiveness, cyanosis, and apnea in an infant, who then resumes breathing with stimulation.",
			"back": "apparent life-threatening event"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-3",
			"front": "To turn white.",
			"back": "blanch"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-4",
			"front": "Slow respiratory rate; an ominous sign in a child that indicates impending respiratory arrest.",
			"back": "bradypnea"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-5",
			"front": "Inflammation of the bronchioles that usually occurs in children younger than 2 years and is often caused by the respiratory syncytial virus.",
			"back": "bronchiolitis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-6",
			"front": "Pulses that are closest to the core (central) part of the body where the vital organs are located; include the carotid, femoral, and apical pulses.",
			"back": "central pulses"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-7",
			"front": "A general term applying to all forms of abuse and neglect of children.",
			"back": "child abuse"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-8",
			"front": "A viral inflammatory disease of the upper respiratory system that may cause a partial airway obstruction and is characterized by a barking cough; usually seen in children.",
			"back": "croup"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-9",
			"front": "A bacterial infection in which the epiglottis becomes inflamed and enlarged and may cause an upper airway obstruction.",
			"back": "epiglottitis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-10",
			"front": "Areas where the neonate’s or infant’s skull has not fused together; usually disappear at approximately 18 months of age.",
			"back": "fontanelles"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-11",
			"front": "A seizure characterized by severe twitching of all of the body’s muscles that may last several minutes or more; formerly known as a grand mal seizure.",
			"back": "generalized seizure"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-12",
			"front": "An “uh” sound heard during exhalation; reflects the child’s attempt to keep the alveoli open; a sign of increased work of breathing.",
			"back": "grunting"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-13",
			"front": "The first year of life.",
			"back": "infancy"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-14",
			"front": "A tape used to estimate an infant’s or child’s weight on the basis of body length; appropriate drug doses and equipment sizes are listed on the tape.",
			"back": "length-based resuscitation tape"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-15",
			"front": "An inflammation of the meningeal coverings of the brain and spinal cord; it is usually caused by a virus or a bacterium.",
			"back": "meningitis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-16",
			"front": "The external openings of the nostrils. A single nostril opening is called a naris.",
			"back": "nares"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-17",
			"front": "Refusal or failure on the part of the parent or caregiver to provide life necessities.",
			"back": "neglect"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-18",
			"front": "A form of bacterial meningitis characterized by rapid onset of symptoms, often leading to shock and death.",
			"back": "Neisseria meningitides"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-19",
			"front": "A structured assessment tool used to rapidly form a general impression of the infant or child without touching him or her; consists of assessing appearance, work of breathing, and circulation to the skin.",
			"back": "pediatric assessment triangle"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-20",
			"front": "A specialized medical practice devoted to the care of the young.",
			"back": "pediatrics"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-21",
			"front": "An airborne bacterial infection that affects mostly children younger than 6 years. Patients will be feverish and exhibit a “whoop” sound on inspiration after a coughing attack; highly contagious through droplet infection.",
			"back": "pertussis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-22",
			"front": "Children between ages 3 and 6 years.",
			"back": "preschool-age"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-23",
			"front": "A person who is 6 to 12 years of age.",
			"back": "school age"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-24",
			"front": "A syndrome seen in abused infants and children; the patient has been subjected to violent, whiplash-type shaking injuries inflicted by the abusing individual that may cause coma, seizures, and increased intracranial pressure due to tearing of the cerebral veins with consequent bleeding into the brain.",
			"back": "shaken baby syndrome"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-25",
			"front": "An upright position in which the patient’s head and chin are thrust slightly forward to keep the airway open.",
			"back": "sniffing position"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-26",
			"front": "Death of an infant or young child that remains unexplained after a complete autopsy.",
			"back": "sudden infant death syndrome"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-27",
			"front": "Rapid respirations.",
			"back": "tachypnea"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-28",
			"front": "A child age 1 to 3 years.",
			"back": "toddler"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-29",
			"front": "Inflammation of the trachea.",
			"back": "tracheitis"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-30",
			"front": "An upright position in which the patient leans forward onto two arms stretched forward and thrusts the head and chin forward.",
			"back": "tripod position"
		},
		{
			"id": "category-chapter-35-tag-vocabulary-card-31",
			"front": "An indicator of oxygenation and ventilation; reflects the child’s attempt to compensate for hypoxia.",
			"back": "work of breathing"
		}
	],
	"category": {
		"value": "chapter-35",
		"label": "Chapter 35"
	},
	"tags": [
		{
			"value": "vocabulary",
			"label": "Vocabulary"
		}
	]
}